Just after 2 a.m.…
半夜两点多…
in my room where I live alone…
在我一个人住的家里
COOLING PADS
（冷敷贴）
sits a high-school boy I met through gaming…
游戏网友的高中男生
and myself with a 37.8-degrees-Celsius fever.
与发烧到37.8度的我
ORIGINAL STORY BY MASHIRO
（原作：Mashiro）
I was fast asleep last night.
我昨天真的睡死了
I'm sorry I didn't notice your call.
完全没注意到电话，抱歉哦
Will this be enough to survive for a week?
准备了这么多 应该够你活一星期了吧
Momo, you're a goddess.
小桃真是女神
Really though, Akane…
话说回来
Whenever you get a fever, it always escalates.
你每次一发烧就会变重症
YOU NEED TO EXERCISE MORE…
（你要练一下身体啦）
You've got no stamina at all.
太缺乏基础体力了
-TAKE OUT WHAT YOU WANT TO CHILL -OKAY
（好 把要冰的东西给我）
-Did you see a doctor? -Uh, yeah.
-有去看医生了吗？ -嗯
Yamada took me to a hospital with a night-time clinic.
山田带我去了晚上有开的医院
I plan to go again tomorrow.
但我明天还要再去一趟
OH, NICE… SHE BOUGHT MEAT TOO!
（哇…还有肉耶）
Huh?
什么？
Oh, right.
就是啊
-Yamada came to check on me yesterday. -He what…?!
-昨天山田有来关心我的状况 -啥？
You didn't start dating without telling me?
你们已经默默交往了？
Of course not! We're just friends.
怎么可能，我们是朋友啦
He really is a nice guy.
他真的是个大好人
Hold it… that sounds like…
这个意思是…
Never mind. I'll wait until she's better.
算了，等你好了再说
DISPLAY OF COMPASSION
（贴心）
That's all for now.
差不多就这样吧
I'll be heading home then.
那我要回去了
Thank you! I'll get some money, so wait here.
谢谢，我去拿钱来，等我一下
Is there really a man
对没有好感的女人
who'd go that far for a woman he doesn't like?
真的有男人愿意做到这个地步？
I doubt it,
虽然让人怀疑
but I don't know anything about Yamada's personality
但我完全不清楚山田的个性
and Akane seems to have set herself
茜好像也因为失恋的关系
high hurdles for love since her break up.
自己把谈恋爱的门槛调高了
I UNDERSTAND HOW SHE FEELS THOUGH
（虽然可以理解啦…）
I ADDED A LITTLE EXTRA
（我多给了一点哦）
THANKS
（了解）
Okay, I'm off.
那我走了
Akane, if anything comes up, tell me right away.
茜，有事要立刻说哦
Oh, and timing is everything when it comes to romance.
还有谈恋爱，要懂得看准时机
Huh? Oh, yeah.
啊…嗯
Right.
是啊
As long as you understand.
你有懂就好
Bye!
拜啦
TEXT FROM AKITO YAMADA
（山田传来新信息）
THANKS FOR TODAY. FEELING OKAY?
（今天真的谢谢你 你那边没事吧？）
SORRY, JUST SAW THIS. I'M FINE.
（抱歉现在才看到，我没事）
WELL, THAT'S GOOD TO HEAR.
（总之放心了）
I have to make it up to him when I'm better.
等病好了，必须好好答谢他
What would he like?
要送什么好呢？
Is your cold okay?
感冒还好吗？
I can log in this weekend.
瑠奈这个周末可以上线哦
Let's game together when you're better!
等你好了，再一起玩游戏吧
-I MISS YOU! -AWW…
（人家好寂寞 感动）
Runa!
瑠奈…
Now that you mention it, I wonder if Runa logged in yesterday.
话说，瑠奈昨天有上线吗？
I was supposed to join her in saying hello to the new member.
原本说好要一起向新人打招呼
I haven't even met her yet.
但我到现在都还没见过对方
I'm tired from studying,
书也读累了
maybe I'll play FOS for a while.
稍微打一下FOS吧
I doubt Runa or Yamada are online,
瑠奈和山田现在应该没上线
but maybe Princess Ruri and Mr. Kamota are.
不晓得瑠璃姬和鸭田先生在不在
I'd love to go hunting together!
好想一起去打怪
SYSTEM: AKANE HAS LOGGED IN
（Akane上线了）
I haven't raised my level recently.
因为最近没怎么在升等
I want to make up for lost time!
我现在想尽情打一下
Oh, it's Akane!
是Akane
Oh, it's the new member I've heard about!
是传闻中的新人
This is our new member, Tsubaki!
这位是新加入的TSUBAKI哦
Nice to meet you! I'm Akane!
幸会！我是Akane
I'm a level 55 paladin!
是等级55的圣骑士
I'm Tsubaki. Nice to meet you.
我是TSUBAKI，请多指教
I've only just started playing.
我是刚开始玩的新手
I was just talking with Tsubaki about exploring the map.
我们正好聊到要一起去侦查地图
But since you're here, Akane, why don't we all go hunting?
但既然你来了 干脆一起去打怪如何？
Sounds great!
我想去！
Huh?
那个…
I'm still learning how to fight.
但我还不太清楚适合的打法
I'd just be a burden to you.
应该会拖累大家
Since you're a paladin,
如果是圣骑士的打法
you should learn from Akane!
建议你可以参考Akane哦
You're a paladin too, Tsubaki?
原来TSUBAKI也是玩圣骑士啊
Are most people mages?
果然玩魔职的人比较多吗？
Everyone around here is a mage with demon-like fire power.
这里只有火力强得像鬼的魔法使
Plus, they all have higher defense than me.
而且所有人的防御力都比我高
Sometimes, I wonder
有时候我甚至会想
why I chose this class in the first place.
自己为何要选择这个职业
I mean, the game says Paladins are the recommended class for beginners.
明明有写说这职业适合新手啊
That may be,
不过
but I believe paladins are powerful when they reach high levels.
我想圣骑士只要练高等级就会很强
They're the only class
像是主线破关后的追加BOSS
that can challenge end game bosses on their own.
好像也只有圣骑士能单独击倒
Sounds fun.
感觉很有挑战价值
I like a good challenge.
我还蛮喜欢的
I GUESS EVERYONE HAS A DIFFERENT APPROACH
（人人都有各自的想法啦）
Wow! She's great!
真是个好人
Even so, I've heard the combat system is difficult--
只是听说打法有点难…
Don't worry!
你放心
Leave it to me!
交给我吧
I'd better set a good example.
我要秀出帅气的一面
I'd better not get in their way.
我要想办法不要拖累大家
Mom!
妈
My donuts are missing!
没看到瑠奈的甜甜圈
Well then, shall we depart?
那就准备出发吧
Have you looked over your equipment?
装备检查好了吗？
Yes.
好了
What a beautiful blue sky!
天空真美
Princess Ruri loves the graphics for the sky in this game!
瑠璃我很喜欢这游戏的天空
It might be my favorite part of FOS.
可能是人家在FOS最爱的部分
What do you two think?
你们觉得如何？
I'm a little busy right now!
我们现在很忙
-Strike! -Shield!
-攻击… -防御…
Um, rather than admiring the scenery, how about helping us out?
话说你别悠哉了 可以来帮忙一下吧？
This monster is really tough!
这敌人的血有够厚
If Ruri attacks, it'll be an instant kill.
瑠璃我攻击的话会秒杀的
This isn't one of the tougher bosses. Just do your best!
这不是多强的BOSS，你们加油
You can't be serious.
骗人的吧？
It has so much HP,
这家伙HP多到爆
there are four bars!
血条有四排耶
ORDINARY ENEMY
（迪梅塔尔 普通的怪）
DAMAGE METER
（恶迪梅塔尔）
The damage you inflict
你们的攻击力
is less than the monster's natural healing ability. It's so funny!
都比不上敌人的自动回血，真好玩
PRINCESS RURI'S HATRED FROM PALADINS INCREASES 2X!
（不爽 瑠璃姬吸引了 两个圣骑士的仇恨）
Watch out, here it comes.
来，要来咯
Darn it!
可恶！
-Strike! -But then…
-攻击… -可是
Strike!
攻击…
NATURAL HEALING POWERS
（自动回血）
It's true.
他说得没错
At this rate, attacks are useless.
这样下去没完没了
Thanks to the Guild Master's healing magic,
多亏有会长的回血魔法
we won't die, but…
我们才没死
TSUBAKI AKANE
（AKANE 血量 TSUBAKI 血量）
Our HP drains fast!
但是被磨掉了好多精力
If you use a little strategy,
对付这个BOSS，只要用点心思
the two of you should be more than capable of defeating it.
现在的你们也完全打得过哦
Oh, I think I understand!
原来如此，我想通了
We may need to mash our skill buttons!
是不是要猛按技能钮？
IS THAT WHAT SHE MEANT BY STRATEGY?
（这算是有用心思吗？）
I've already been pushing them repeatedly.
可是我已经在狂按各种钮了
Let's try it.
就试试看吧
We'll mash to our deaths.
疯狂连打战术
One, two, three…
预备…开始
MASH
（按…）
THE MASTER SENSES SOMETHING
（聊天室没人说话）
SINCE THE CHAT HAS GONE QUIET
（察觉到状况的会长）
GROAN
（不爽）
They must be really mashing their buttons.
她们一定在疯狂连打吧
Would you like a hint?
要不要我提示呢？
Wait!
等等
-I think I've figured it out. -For real?
-我好像有点懂了 -真的假的？
Maybe… don't say anything yet.
可能…请先别说出提示
Sure thing!
好
HINT, PLEASE!
（给我提示啦）
AFTER WHAT FELT LIKE 500 MILLION YEARS
（体感五亿年）
My fingers are numb.
我的手指已经挂了
Mine too.
我也是
But in the second half,
但是在后半段
we got its HP down pretty low, right?
其实砍了很多血吧
It was almost as if there was a specific time when attacks were effective.
好像有个适合攻击的时机
Right!
对…
When it spread its wings!
像是张开翅膀的时候
Maybe we need to inflict damage efficiently in those moments.
趁那时候集中火力，或许行得通
Which means we save our mashing for then!
所以要在那里狂按技能
Do you mind if we check each other's skills?
要不要再确认我们的技能效果？
Sure! Let's look over our equipment too.
也是，也重新检查装备吧
They're friends already.
已经变成朋友了
TSUBAKI: MY ARMOR IS RUINED. I'M GONNA TAKE A BREAK.
（防具都破损了，我先休息一下）
AKANE: I'M GOING TO LOG OFF! BYE!
（我先下线了，两位下次见）
PRINCESS RURI: OKAY! THANKS! GOOD WORK!
（好，Akane辛苦了）
PRINCESS RURI: I'LL REPAIR YOUR ARMOR, TSUBAKI.
（TSUBAKI 防具给我修理吧）
TSUBAKI: THANK YOU, AKANE.
（Akane，辛苦了）
TSUBAKI: TAKING MY ARMOR OFF NOW.
（我现在脱防具）
Her name's Akane and she's in my guild.
同一个公会的Akane
Which means she's probably the one.
这么说来，应该是那个人吧
AKANE HAS SENT YOU A FRIEND REQUEST
（收到Akane的好友申请）
She was pretty easy to talk to.
是个很好聊的人啊
ARE YOU AWAKE?
（你还醒着吗？）
YES.
（醒着）
AKANE CALLING
（茜来电）
Hello?
是的
Huh?
什么？
The Evil Dimitar?
凶恶迪梅塔尔？
What is this about?
你在说什么？
The monster you encounter in the field,
离开FOS的初始城市
right after leaving the FOS starter town.
在第一个草原会遇到
The one with four bars of HP.
HP有四排的大怪物
You mean a randomly appearing boss?
你说随机出现的BOSS？
Yeah, like that!
对…
Princess Ruri said the same thing.
瑠璃姬也是那么说
Have you ever defeated it?
你有打倒过那个怪吗？
I haven't fought many bosses of that rank.
我很少打那种等级的BOSS
I see…
这样啊
I was wondering if there was a secret to beating it.
我还以为你有什么攻略法
Well…
天晓得…
If it has a gimmick,
如果有什么机制的话
you should adjust your maneuvers to that.
就是看准时机行动吧
THE EVIL DIMITAR
（凶恶迪梅塔尔）
A gimmick?
机制…
Like moments when attacks are ineffective or something.
像是有一段攻击无效的期间
There are many patterns.
也有分成很多情况
Right! Yeah, that happened!
对！那倒是有
What should I do in those moments?
这种时候该怎么做才好？
Buff?
buff？
Oh, I see!
原来如此
So, do you like our guild?
你还喜欢我们的公会吗？
USING WEAVING SKILL TO FIX ARMOR
（用裁缝技能修理防具中）
Akane's easy to talk to, right?
Akane是很好聊的人吧？
Uh, yeah.
啊，是的
Everyone's been nice.
大家都很亲切
I'm quite relieved.
我感到放心多了
To the point that I feel guilty.
反而是我不太好意思
Why's that?
为什么？
In the past…
原本…
I wasn't really interested in this game.
我对这个游戏没什么兴趣
You could say I joined your guild for more selfish reasons.
我算是因为个人理由才加入这公会
And yet, now…
但是该怎么说
I'm no longer sure what it was that I even wanted to do.
我现在已经不晓得自己想做什么了
Are you all right? If you have a problem, Ruri's happy to listen!
你还好吗？瑠璃我可以听你说哦
TSUBAKI: THERE'S NOTHING
（我并没有）
TSUBAKI: TO TALK ABOUT.
（什么话想说）
I've merely been watching. That's all.
我只是在一旁看着
I've done nothing more
然后就这样…
than watch in fear.
一直害怕行动
There's nothing to it.
什么事也没有
I just don't have the courage to act.
我只是没有行动的勇气而已
THERE'S NOTHING TO TALK ABOUT?
（没有话想要说？）
SHE DOESN'T HAVE THE COURAGE TO ACT?
（没有行动的勇气？）
Umm… I'm not sure what this is about,
那个…虽然人家搞不清楚
but what if you try acting first?
那你可以试着行动看看啊
If there's something you want to do,
既然你有想做的事
couldn't you just give it a try?
那就尝试看看如何？
If you wait for courage or motivation, you could wait forever!
勇气和干劲不是等了就会来
Sometimes, you have to act first!
先懂得行动再说
If there's something you want to change…
如果你有想改变什么的话
And then…
然后啊…
Oh no, look at the time.
糟糕，已经这么晚了
Sorry, I've been rambling on and on.
抱歉，我不小心说个没完
-You must be tired. -Yeah.
-你一定听累了吧？ -没错
My hand got so numb, I switched to Bluetooth.
因为手太累，我就换成蓝牙耳机了
Honest as always, huh?
真老实
In the end, what was it that you wanted to ask?
结果你找我到底有什么事？
Oh…
这个嘛
Well, it's more like…
嗯，说是有事…
I wanted to hear your voice.
就是想听你的声音
That's all. Bye!
只是这样，再见
AKANE CALL TERMINATED
（通话结束）
M… My hands…
手…我的手…
are shaking.
在发抖
Momo?
小桃？
Thanks for earlier.
刚才谢谢你了
Is this a good time?
现在方便吗？
Well, you see…
那个…
There's something I want to talk about, after all.
我还是有话想跟小桃说
MOMO: HERE'S A CAFE I WANT TO GO TO
（小桃：明天的碰面地点 我有想去的咖啡厅）
CAN WE TALK THERE?
（约那里好吗？传地图给你）
-TOMORROW AT 11. -OKAY
（小桃：就约11点集合 茜：好！）
Here, huh?
是这里啊
CUTE PLACE
（真可爱）
I never noticed this place.
原来还有这样的店啊
Anyway…
然后啊
what I wanted to talk about on the phone was…
我上次在电话里想问你的事…
Why…?
就是你觉得…
Why do you think he dumped me?
我为什么会被甩？
Your order, please.
请问要点什么？
I'd like souffle pancakes and an iced tea.
我要软嫩舒芙蕾松饼和冰红茶
-She'll be fine with water. -You're awful!
-这个女生给她水就好 -真过分
SOUFFLE PANCAKES
（软嫩舒芙蕾松饼）
Same as her, please!
我也要点一样的
Pancakes and iced tea, two items for each of you.
松饼和冰红茶，各两份吧？
Akane, I'm disappointed in you.
茜，我对你太失望了
But why?!
为什么啦？
There's something I want to talk about.
我有话想跟你说
For real?! Oh, but wait!
真的假的？等等！
I want to talk in person!
我想直接见面聊
Somewhere we can sit down!
好好促膝长谈
FINALLY!
（终于要说了？）
While I waited a whole week for your cold to mend,
之后在等你病好的这一星期
I could barely contain myself
小桃我也坐立难安
and I only went on three blind dates.
途中只参加了三次联谊
And yet, when I finally get to hear you out,
结果现在听你开口
the idiocy of your conversation starter exceeded my wildest imagination.
却是超乎想象的无聊内容
Such a disappointment.
我太失望了
Three times in a week sounds like a lot to me.
一星期联谊三次，是火力全开吧
And here I thought I'd be treated to some fun romantic talk!
还以为能听到快乐的恋爱话题
Let me finish, okay?
听我说到最后啦
These days, I wonder about something.
我最近突然在想
And I mean this
就是那个…
in terms of my love life…
关于恋爱那方面的事
In order for me to move forward,
为了让自己往前迈进
if there's something majorly wrong with me, I want to fix it.
我想改正一下自己的糟糕缺点
It could be that I'm just unaware.
说不定我有什么自己没发现
Maybe I have some terrible habits!
但其实很扯的坏习惯
Where did you get that idea?
这是什么神奇思考？
When I think it's possible that I have some fatal flaw
像是不改掉某个地方 跟谁谈恋爱都没用
that will ruin any romantic relationship I try, I get so scared--
一想到自己可能有个致命缺点 我就好怕
There's nothing.
你才没有
If I'd known I would worry like this later,
既然会烦恼成这样
should I have abandoned my pride
早知道就算丢脸
and asked Takuma the reason?
当时应该向拓马问清楚原因才对
Um, I don't think--
不，这个嘛..
NOT A GOOD IDEA…
（那不对吧…）
Welcome!
欢迎光临
What's this?
奇怪？
Um, excuse me, gentlemen--
不好意思，客人…
I thought I saw someone cute, and it turns out to be Momo!
还以为是哪个正妹，原来是小桃
What a coincidence!
有够巧的
-Excuse me… -Wh… Who's he?
-是谁？ -那个…带位…
-A guy from a blind date. -We're fine!
-前天联谊的人 -我们坐这里就好
-Um, sir… -He couldn't keep his hands to himself…
-因为有够缠人，又爱动手动脚 -两位客人
-I really-- -And I left right away.
-人家马上就走了 -请你们往这边…
Just who is setting up these blind dates for you?
你到底都跟哪种人联谊啊？
Friends of friends of friends…
是别人辗转介绍的啦
Mind if I sit here?
可以一起坐吗？
No way!
不行！
And hello to your lovely friend.
小桃的朋友，你好啊
-What'll you have? -I'm really sorry.
-要喝什么？ -真的很抱歉
I'll take care of this,
小桃我会想办法
so just ignore them!
你无视他们就好
Aren't you being a bit pushy?
你们太霸道了吧
Momo is clearly bothered.
给小桃带来困扰了
Right? We're such a nuisance, us two.
对啊，我们超烦人的吧？
Say, Momo!
小桃
You fled without paying, didn't you?
你没付前阵子的酒钱吧？
I gave my money to the organizer.
我都有好好交给主办人啊
Oh? That's not what I heard.
可是我都没听说耶
Did you ask her directly?
你有向本人确认过了吗？
Who cares? It was a few drinks.
酒钱也没什么大不了啦
Let's try and get along.
大家好好相处嘛
At this rate, they're not gonna leave.
看情况，他们好像会待一阵子
Say Momo, you sure smell nice!
小桃，你身上好香哦
-No way! Too close! -Excuse me!
-不要！你靠太近了 -欸，等等…
Sorry to keep you waiting.
久等了
Here are your souffle pancakes and ice tea.
这边是松软舒芙蕾松饼和冰红茶…
Wait… Was this a table of four?
奇怪？这桌是四位客人吗？
-Eita! -Sasaki! Actually, that table…
-瑛…瑛太 -佐佐木，其实那一桌…
Oh my.
哎呀
We know each other, so…
我们认识啦
Don't worry about it!
用不着在意
EITA! HELP!
（是瑛太！救救我们）
A GUILD MEMBER'S PLEADING EYES
（来自公会成员的视线）
Excuse me, sir. I apologize,
两位客人，非常抱歉
but I can't allow you to trouble our other customers.
因为带给其他客人困扰了
I'll happily guide you to another table.
我带你们到其他座位
We're fine here.
我们坐这就行了
I apologize,
真是非常抱歉
but I can't allow you to trouble our other customers.
两位带给其他客人困扰了
Please move to another table.
麻烦移至其他座位
-I told you, we're-- -Your cooperation is appreciated.
-不，我们坐这里… -感谢两位的协助
Oh, Eita! Thanks!
瑛太，谢谢你
What a coincidence!
真巧耶
You startled me! I didn't notice it was you.
吓到我了，我完全没发现
I noticed you though.
我倒是早就注意到了
Say something then!
那你应该叫我嘛
It was more fun staying quiet.
我想说这样比较好玩
They know each other?
是认识的人？
Excuse me…
那个…
I'm sorry for causing trouble for your establishment.
给店里带来麻烦，真是抱歉
Not at all.
不会
Man, what a surprise!
吓死我了
Thank god Eita was here, huh?
幸好有瑛太在
That is one hot guy.
那个人长得超帅耶
-Eita's in my FOS guild too. -Oh my!
-瑛太也是同个游戏公会的人 -耶！
Seriously? Him too?!
啥？那个人也是？
Yeah! He's the Guild Master.
嗯，他是公会会长
That game you play offers better dreams than blind dates, huh?
你玩的游戏比联谊还有希望
I'm starting to feel like a fool.
让我开始感到好空虚
I'M NOT SO SURE ABOUT THAT.
（该怎么说呢…）
Momo…
小桃
Back to what we were talking about…
关于刚才的话题
Good work, today.
辛苦了
Oh, hey Sasaki! Got a moment?
佐佐木，现在方便吗？
Huh? Afraid not.
不方便
Why, you ask? Because I'm done for the day.
因为人家已经下班了
It's not about work!
我不是说工作的事
All of us on the afternoon shift are going to karaoke later.
午班的人等一下要去唱KTV
Want to come?
要不要一起来？
Since you helped me out, it's my treat.
刚才你帮了我忙，我请你
My little sister is waiting for me. No can do!
我妹在等我回家，所以没办法
Sister complex!
这个妹控
How rude!
真没礼貌
I just happen to love her too much.
我只是给妹妹多一点爱而已
So, a sister complex.
也就是妹控
You even admit it!
你承认了啊
Bye now!
辛苦了
Hey, Eita!
那个…瑛太
Huh? You two are still here?
奇怪？你们两个还在啊
What are you doing?
你们在做什么？
There's nothing in this area.
这里什么都没有啊
We were waiting for you, Eita!
我们是在等你
Oh my! Waiting for Ruri?
讨厌！等我下班？
That's his personality?!
好妙的性格
There's something I want to tell you.
我有话想跟你说
Do you have time?
方便吗？
Shall we go then?
那就准备出发吧
Have you looked over your equipment?
装备检查好了吗？
-Yes. -Yes!
-好了 -好了！
I'd better set a good example.
我要秀出帅气的一面
Equipment…
装备…
SEARCHING INVENTORY
（装备确认中）
Wait a minute,
话说回来
isn't your equipment a bit different from mine, Tsubaki?
TSUBAKI的装备 是不是和我有点不同？
How cool! Are those rare items?
感觉好帅哦，是稀有装备吗？
Uh, not exactly…
不是…
SHE GOT THEM EASILY ON THE MAIN QUEST
（破完主线任务就拿到了）
Come on! Tell me how you found them!
欸，这些要怎么拿到手？
I didn't "find them" or anything.
也不是在哪里拿到的
-On my first quest, I-- -Yeah? Go on!
-就是初期的任务… -嗯，然后呢？
On the contrary, players like Akane who've maxed out
不如说把初始装备强化到MAX
their default equipment are super rare.
Akane这种玩家才是超少见啊
I'M JEALOUS
（好羡慕哦）
MAX DEFAULT EQUIPMENT MAX GRAPHICS CARD
（初始装备MAX，显卡盒MAX）